In this video we'll talk about linters in general and ESLint in particular.
This topic is not connected directly to webpack. You can use ESLint and even if you don't use Webpack
in your project.
Therefore this video is optional and is not required in order to understand how webpack works.
However, I think that the information presented in this video is useful for you
if you plan to work on any javascript project. So what is a linter?
According to Wikipedia a linter refers to tools that analyze the source code to flag programming errors,
bugs, stylistic errors, and suspicious constructs.
The term originates from a Unix utility that examined C language source code.
The term is now applied generically to tools that flag suspicious code in software written in any programming
language.
Linters can warn you about syntax errors,
uses of undeclared variables, calls to deprecated functions, spacing and formatting conventions, and much
more.
There are linters for almost every programming language. But in this video we are going to talk about
ESLint.
ESLint is an open source project that provides a pluggable linting  utility for JavaScript.
It is highly configurable and you can optimize it for the specific needs of your project.
I'll show you how to install ESLint for this project associated with this course. If you want to repeat
all the steps on your local computer, you would need to clone this repository.
And check out the branch
which is called starting-point-for-use-cases.
So let me show you how to configure linting for this project.
First, we need to install ESLint.
This will install ESLint into node_modules folder of this project.
Now let's go to the editor and add an NPM script that will run ESLint for us. I will go to the
package.json.
And here we have the list of scripts. I will add a new script which we'll call lint. And here I will
just specify the eslint without any additional options.
So now we need to create a configuration file for
ESLint.
This file is called .eslintrc and it uses json format. So let me create this file in the root directory
of the project
Here in this file
we can specify the rules, and according to these rules ESLint will inspect our code.
All ESLint are configurable, and on this page you can see a list of all the rules. As you can see
the list of rules is quite big.
It's quite hard to specify each and every rule with its specific configuration.
However, if you want to do that, it's possible. If you look at this list you will notice that some rules
have checkmarks. These rules are widely used and they check the most common problems. They are so common
that there is a shortcut in order to apply them all.
And this requires only one line of code. So here, inside the ESLint configuration file,
I will add extends eslint:recommended. And this line tells ESLint to apply only the rules with checkmarks
that we have seen just now.
But this is not all we need.
By default ESLint checks javascript code against Ecmascript 5 standard. However we use Ecmascript
6 in this project. That requires us to configure a couple more options inside ESLint configuration file.
So below this line we need to specify parser options.
And here we can specify the Ecmascript version.
and we will put six here.
And besides that we need to specify sourcetype module.
So the sourcetype allows us to use Ecmascript six modules. Otherwise ESLint would complain about import
and export keywords.
If we run ESLint now,
we will see a bunch of errors related to require function and document variable.
We need to teach ESLint that it should not complain about require function inside the webpack configuration
files. Because the require function is defined when you run our build from the terminal using node js.
For this
we need to tell ESLint that we are using node js environment.
Here we can specify env option and inside
we can say that we are using a node environment.
So now ESLint
will know that require function is defined and it will not complain about it anymore.
We also need to tell you need to not complain when it finds document variable inside our components
because that code will be executed in the browser environment. And inside of the browser environment
we have a document variable defined. So here we will also specify that we are using browser environment.
There is one more thing.
If you remember, we are using class properties in our project which is not part of official ecmascript specification
yet.
ESLint will complain about it as well.
This line here refers to class properties.
So in order to fix this we need to use another parser for ESLint which is called
babel-eslint.
First we need to install this parser.
Now we can add it to the eslint configuration file.
Here we just specify parser babel-eslint.
If we run
eslint
now,
it will not complain about class properties anymore.
So now the only thing that is left is errors about the console.log statements that we have throughout
the project.
These errors.
In order to remove this errors,
we need to configure one more rule that checks for a console.log statements.
This rule is called no-console. By default
eslint:recommended thing includes the rule that does not allow us to use console. log
statements, but for the purpose of this project
we need them.
So we need to override this rule.
All the rules are specified inside the rules object
And here we can say that no-console rule should be turned off.
So zero here means that this rule is turned off. If we run eslint in the terminal now, we will see that
there are no complaints anymore.
So far every time we needed to check our code for linting errors, we went to a terminal and ran a command
there.
But there is a way to setup linter inside the editor, so we can see the errors right away, without going to
the terminal.
For every editor I know there is a plugin for eslint.
Since we are using Atom in this course,
I'll show you how to install eslint for Atom.
First,
we need to go to the Atom preferences.
And here we need to go to the tab called install. We need to install two packages here.
First one is called linter.
And I already have this package installed. And the second package is called linter-eslint.
I have this package as well.
Okay so these packages are installed. So let's check how this works.
I will go to hello-world-button.js file and intentionally make an error somewhere in the code.
So let's say we made a mistake, like a small typo, and instead of button we wrote batton. And immediately
you can see a red circle to the left.
If I hover my mouse on this circle,
I will see a message saying "batton is not defined". In general, code linting is the process of static code
analysis that can help you discover bugs early on in the development process.
It can help you avoid spending half an hour of your time debugging production code just to find out
that there is a typo in the name of the variable or something like that. Of course,
eslint cannot find a more complex bugs related to the business logic of your application. But at least
it helps you to avoid dummy mistakes.
There is actually one more area where eslint can be applied.
eslint can help your team to define and follow a common coding standards which will make your project
look like it was written by a single person.
I saw several teams using eslint specifically for this purpose.