In this video we will think about Why. Why do we need Webpack at all?
Back in the days when dinosaurs were walking on Earth and nobody heard about an iPhone,
web applications look like this.
Here we can see that several CSS files are included at the top of the HTML file. But that is not the
first thing here.
Do you see how many JavaScript files we have here?
Eleven! Eleven! And some of them depend on each other!
Of course it is easy to tell that almost everything probably depends on the common.js because of
its name. But would you guess in the first 5 minutes
that's the shipping.js depends on user.js  because user.js handles the address of the customer?
If you accidentally change the order of the JavaScript files,
this project might break. When I only started my career,
all that applications look like this. But then we started to use grunt and gulp. These tools helped us to
manage assets and  concatenate all our JavaScript files into one. But they still can't figure out
dependencies between those files.
In order to manage JavaScript dependencies we used require.js which helps in a way. But it is
not as powerful as Webpack. Webpack is a static module bundler for modern javascript applications.
When Webpack processes your application, it recursively builds a dependency graph that includes every
module in your application. And then packages all of those modules into one or more bundles.
When I started using Webpack, most of my projects started to look like this.
There are only 2 files here: 1 file for CSS and 1 file for JavaScript.
There are no hidden dependencies.
You don't have to worry about the correct order of the files anymore.
There is only one JavaScript file we need to include! All dependencies, internal and external, are bundled
inside this file.
Basically, Webpack is a single tool for managing all of your code as well as assets in 1 place. It can
handle javascript, typescript, coffeescript, CSS, SASS, LESS, images, and so much more! In 3 words, Webpack
is all in one. I think by this point you already know why we need Webpack.
Let's go further and learn how to use it.