In this video we are going to create a basic setup for the future videos.
We want to touch what back yet.
So if you like you can skip to the next video.
We are going to create a simple project with only three files one HDMI file and two JavaScript files.
I've already created an empty folder for our project called tutorial and I opened this empty folder
in a text editor.
Basically you can use any editor of a choice like visual studio called Web storm sublime text etc..
First I'm going to create an HD email file with the name index that HDMI
I will paste here a simple content that I prepared beforehand.
This is a very simple HDMI page nothing special is going on here.
I am specifying a title character set which is UTF eight inside the body tag.
I am including two JavaScript files that we don't have at the moment but I'm going to grade them right
now.
I'm going to put these files into a separate folder called that's ever seen so I need to create this
folder.
Now
first I'm going to create Hello World dot J S file
there will be only one function here called Hello World.
This will be a pretty basic function.
It will print a simple string Hello World to the browser console
the function is done.
Let's invoke this function you're going to invoke it from another file that I'm going to create right
now.
This file will have a name index that J S so I will invoke the hello world function from here
as you can see the function definition is located inside.
Hello World dot J S file and we invoke this function from a different file index that J as in other
words index that Jesus file depends on.
Hello World note J S file
let's have a look how it works in the browser Heigl copy it it will pass and go to the browser
I don't paste of this pass to the navigation bar and currently we have an empty page here but if I go
to the developer tools and have a look in the console top you will see a jealous script error saying
hello world is not defined at index that G S so why do you think we have this error
if I go back to the editor and have a look at index dot J S file I you'll see the function invocation
here however the browser says that it's not defined.
Actually the issue is not connected to this file.
The issue is connected to HDMI all file these these two script tags you see index that Jesus is included
before hello world that J S however it should be included after because inside the index that Jesus
you are using a function that's defined inside hello world that J S here we are using hello world function
and here this function is defined therefore the order of this lines is wrong I need to change the order
I need to put index that Jesus after hello world not J S so as a function declaration comes before the
function invocation let's have a look at the browser again and check if everything works now I refresh
in my page and now we see hello world string in the browser console.
So basically we are done is our set up they're going to use it in the future read years in the next
video they're going to integrate right back into our project.