In the previous video we created a simple application.
It is one HDMI file and two JavaScript files in this video.
We are going to integrate that into our application.
Let's have a look at our index.
HDMI out.
There are only two JavaScript files in the project and we already have to remember the order in which
we need to put our script tags.
Imagine that we have 20 JavaScript files or even 50 JavaScript files maintained in such kind of a project
would quickly become a nightmare.
And these numbers are not exaggerated.
For example one of my latest projects consists of 44 internal modules and 36 external dependencies.
Luckily wetback can manage all those dependencies for us and conveniently bundle them into a single
JavaScript file that includes all of the code needed for the application.
Rat Pack.
We don't have to include so many different dependencies as script takes in a specific order.
We only need to include one JavaScript file that includes all other dependencies.
This file is an entry point for all your dependencies and you don't have to remember the order of the
files were back.
We'll sort that out for you.
So let's install what back but before that we need to generate a simple package not Jason File for our
project.
The package that Jason keeps track of all dependencies needed for the application including right back
in order to do that we need to go to the terminal end to run a simple comment
this comment will generate the default package not Jason for our project.
Now we can install wetback
I am installing two packages here one is pack and another one is wetback minus si a line
and I am using minus minus save minus the option minus minus save minus that option will add work back
to the package that Jason has a development dependency.
If another developer would like to work on this project then you'll see all the dependencies listed
inside the package.
Jason what's more they will be able to install all these dependencies using a single command.
Now when my back is included inside our application we need to configure it what bag stores its configuration
in a javascript file typically named by PAC not config not J S let's create this file.
I'm going to create this file in the root director of the project
now I need to specify a minimal pack configuration inside this file.
This is an object inside this object.
We can specify multiple configuration options.
First option is going to be an entry point
this file usually imports all other dependencies pack it will start from this file when running as build
process.
In our case this is index that J is the second option is an output file.
Here we can specify a name on the file which will be generated as a result of the pack build and passed
to the directory where this file should be generated.
In our case this is bundle that J S which will be generated inside the list directory
so after that back runs it will generate a file named bundle that J has inside of the directory named
D
Westpac will automatically create this directory if it does not exist.
And the last mandatory option is mode for now.
I have specified none here but later in this course I will explain why we need this option and how to
use it in order to run a pack more conveniently we can create a script inside package that Jason.
If I go to the package not Jason I will see a list of scripts here for now.
There is on the test script which does nothing.
It was automatically generated by default when we created our package that Jason
so I will add a new script here named built every time if you run this script it will just run right
back for us.