Now let's use our shiny new epic to.
Let's go to the HDMI file and remove the first script tag.
We don't need it anymore.
From now on if you only need one JavaScript file which includes all the code.
But in order for this to work we need to explicitly import our dependencies inside JavaScript files.
So let's go to the index.
J Yes.
And import hello world function there.
So before using the hello world function we need to import it
I'm important.
Hello world function from hello world dot J S file which is located inside the same directory as index
that G is.
We also need to explicitly export hello world function from hello world dot J S file.
So I'm going to this file and here at the end of the file I will export hello world function
and this syntax that I am using here is a must create six modules web Peg supports my script six modules
my default
my the way if I go to our index dot HDMI Well I can see here that our script tag includes indexed lot
J S but this is not true anymore because what we actually need is a result in bundle when a pack runs
it creates the resulting bundle inside the list folder we need to include this result in bundle here.
So I will replace SLC index that G S with list slash bundle dot J S this is what we specified inside
our of a pack configuration file.
Now let's go to the terminal and run our built again.
Okay.
It turns out that pack shows an error here this error is quite popular.
That's why I'm showing it here.
I hope when you encounter such an error unintentionally you will know how to fix it.
So what this process is that we specified a related pass to the output pass configuration option but
instead we need to specify an absolute pass to the least folder.
So let's go to our Ed and fix it
there is a note J.S. package that helps us to generate absolute passes.
It is called path.
We need to import at first
please note that here I am using the old way of importing modules Coleman J S because inside a pack
configuration file we cannot use EC must create six modules.
So what I need to do I need to replace this related pass with an absolute pass
pass total resolve function converts a sequence of pass segments into an absolute POS
as the first argument I will specify the current directory and as the second argument I will specify
the relative past to the least directory.
Let's go back to the terminal and check if this works
it seems everything works fine.
Let's go to the editor and check it
now.
You can see that wetback created a new folder is the name D.
And inside this folder there is a new file is the name bundle dot J S.
Now let's go to the browser and check if our hello world application still works.
I'll refresh my page now and you can see the hello world in the browser console.
As you can see the application still works and we have now web back included into the application.
So in this video we have learned how to integrate web pack into our application.