In this video you're going to learn how to use custom font with web back.
I'm going to use the single page version of the application as a starting point for this video.
If you want to repeat all the steps on your local computer you would need to clone this repository
and then switch to this branch.
Don't forget to run npm install after you switch branches.
Currently we are using default funds for everything on this page.
Often times web applications look much better when they utilize custom fonts instead of the default
ones.
I'm going to overwrite is a default font with some sound more appealing to the users
the first link on the Google results page is the right one
on this page you can see houses want.
Looks like you can even type here your own text.
Now I need to download this font and put it inside my application.
These are the files containing my custom font.
I don't need all of the variations for my application.
I will need only three of them.
As you can see all of the files use the F format.
I want to provide a couple of more formats to my customers.
There is a website which you can use in order to convert your font to other formats as well.
Here I can choose which formats I need
now.
I can drag my font files from my computer
next.
I'm going to click on the Done button and wait until my font is converted to all of the formats I need
it seems the conversion is done.
Let's download the converted files
here.
We have one variation of our font in three different formats.
Let's move these files into our application.
I need to create a folder where I'm going to store this fonts
now I can move the a custom font files into this folder
next.
Let's use this font inside is application.
I'm going to make it as a default font for all elements on the page
I will create another SPSS file that will affect the whole application
in order to tell the browser that we are going to use a custom font.
We need to use font face CSA as a rule the font face see essence rule specifies a custom font with which
to display the text by allowing authors to provide their own fonts font face makes it possible to design
content without being limited to the so-called Web safe font web safe.
Phones are the funds which are so common that they consider it to be universally available.
First I need to specify the font family.
This would be the name I can use later in order to apply this custom font to various DOM elements.
Now I'm going to specify the font weight for this custom font.
We have three variations of the same open Sans font but they have different font weight.
This property will help us to distinguish between multiple font variations.
Now we need to specify the location of the files.
That store is a custom font.
I'm going to provide three formats in order to increase browser support
had the moment you specified only one font face these font face declares the light font which has font
weight 300.
Now I need to specify two more font faces in order to cover two other font variations.
This one will cover font for it.
and this one will cover font weight six hundred
now I need to specify our custom font as the default font
the default font it will be 300.
Now I need to import this file before any other files in this application
there is only one thing left before we are done.
We need to configure repack so it can understand font files.
I will go to the VAT pack configuration file in order to load funds I need to add an extra rule to the
wrapper configuration
we need to support at least three formats for storing funds.
We are going to use a file loader in order to import funds into the project.
This will preserve the file name and extension when generating files in the dust folder.
This will create a sub folder named funds inside the list folder.
I changed the development of a pack configuration.
Now let's add the same rule to the production configuration.
Make sure you have the file loader installed.
If you followed all the videos you should have it already installed on your computer in case you don't.
You just need to run one simple comment from a terminal
that's all.
Now let's go to the browser and check if this actually works.
As you can see everything works all the text on the page is render it using the custom font we provided.
So in this video you have seen how you can use custom fonts with web Westpac.