In this video I'm going to integrate Jake Query into wetback.
For those of you quote never use Jake wording this is a fast small and feature reached javascript library.
It can make a lot of things much simpler.
For example things like Don't manipulation event handling animation etc..
What's more it works in each and every browser.
I know you can learn more about Jake worry if you go to the website.
Jake dot com let's not have a look at our current application.
We have a single page application with the heading and a button.
Hello world.
If I click on the button it displays some text underneath.
So far be great that everyone here you when you let jealous creep in this video.
I would like to rewrite the hedging component using trickery and then we can compare this to Gordon's
first version using when you like Javascript and the second version using J query.
First I need to install Jacquard.
There is a possibility to reinstall January as NPM package
now.
January is installed.
I am using minus minus safe option because tickler is a production dependency.
Now when we have checked were installed let's import it I will go to the in component because I want
to rewrite this component using Jaguar
so no I will import Jan at the top of the file.
Now we have dollar variable imported from Jaguar library.
Let's modify the component in order to use a query instead of funny like Javascript so here you go using
document create element which is when you like Javascript and I will write it to dollar sign and here
if you need to specify HDMI I'll take each one and these basically is doing the same as document grade
element but it returns and requiring object here.
So now we need to rewrite the second line which is document quality selector and these can also replaced
with a dollar sign but without this angle brackets so these do search and find a body DOM element inside
our page.
Now let's go to the next line.
And here we have each one vote in our demo and these we can rewrite trajectory as well.
So each one is a joke very object no and this object has text method so I can write here.
Text this is a method and insight I will pass on our stream.
And the last line and be also rewritten.
Body is I take very object and it has a similar method to apply and child what it is called append and
it basically does absolutely the same as a brand child.
It seems we are done for now.
Let's have a look at our code.
It looks more concise now but still works the same way as before.
Is it better than before.
For some people yes for some people no.
There are pros and cons in each approach use January.
You can write less code and it looks more concise.
On the other hand you need to include Jake Query in your javascript bundle and this means additional
85 kilobytes
another benefit of Jake worry is that there are tons of security plugins on the internet which can do
everything you can imagine.
If you want to use any of these plugins you must have regularly installed.
Now let's run it back and check our page in the browser.
As you can see our page still works the same way it is before but now we are using Jacquard.