I have created a new Github repository for this course. In this video
I will show you how you can use this repository.
First of all you don't have to use it.
Lessons are designed to be smooth and easy to understand.
But if you are stuck for some reason this repository will really help you.
You can see the link to the repository on your screen.
If I click on this link, I will go to the github.
Now we need to clone this repository to our computer.
We need to copy this link from here.
And then go to the terminal. Here we need to run the following command: "git clone".
And then we paste our link that we have just copied.
This will create a folder with a name webpack-tutorial.
Let's go to that folder.
This repository
is all about branches.
There is a branch for each lesson that requires code changes. Actually there are even two branches
for each lesson.
First branch points to the beginning of the lesson.
It contains all the code that is needed to start the lesson.
The name of the branch corresponds to the name of the lesson - but with small letters and dashes -
and contains suffix "-begin". Second branch points to the end of the lesson.
It shows you how your project should look like at the end of that lesson.
The name of the branch corresponds to the name of the lesson.
But with small letters and dashes and contains suffix "-end".
Here you can see the naming pattern of the branches. Both branches have almost identical names but the first
one ends with "-begin"
and the second one ends with suffix "-end".
Let's assume you are about to begin the lesson "Integrating Express.js in a Single Page Application"
which is part of the section number 7. Then you need to checkout the branch that is pointing
to the beginning of that lesson.
Let's go to the terminal and find that branch
We can list all branches that exist in this repository by running the following command.
This is a pretty long list.
The good thing is that this list is sorted alphabetically.
Each branch in this list has a prefix "remotes/origin" which indicates that this branch is remote.
It seems that this is the branch we are looking for. It is called
"Integrating Express.js into a Single
Page Application Begin".
In order to checkout this branch we need to run the following command.
I will paste the name of this branch and remove the "remote/origin" from here.
And then I will again paste the name of this branch.
But I will leave "remote/origin".
After we have switched to a new branch we need to run "npm install".
At this point
we have all the files needed to follow the lesson.
"Integrating Express.js in a Single Page Application".
If you want to see how the code should look like at the end of this lesson you can checkout another
branch with a similar name but with suffix "-end".  I will find this command of checking the branch
and here I will replace "begin" with "end". Here and here as well.
It may happen that you have some changes in your working directory. Then before switching a branch
You would need to discard those changes.
And then you can switch to the new branch.
Every time you switch to the new branch,
there is a need to run "npm install".
Now you can open your editor and browse the code.
As I said in the beginning of this video, you don't have to repeat all these steps for every single lesson.
But if you're stuck in the middle of the course this repository will definitely help you.