I hope you enjoyed this course and learned a lot of new things for yourself.
Let's do a quick recap or what we have done so far.
First we created a small application with only two javascript files.
Then we integrated webpack into our application.
Then we looked at the webpack loaders and learned how to import CSS, images, and lots of other stuff into
our application.
we also have seen how we can use latest cutting edge javascript features in our applications, even though
they are not implemented in all major browsers yet.
After that we looked at several webpack plugins and learned how to extract css into a separate bundle, and
how to generate html files.
We talked about browser caching and how webpack can help us with that.
Then we talked about the differences between production and development builds and optimized our webpack
configurations for these use cases.
We also talked about multi-page applications and how we can handle common dependencies between several
pages.
Finally, we learned how to integrate express.js framework both for single page applications and for multi-page
applications.
It was a nice journey and we had a lot of fun together.
I hope you enjoyed watching this course as much as I enjoyed creating it.
Have a nice day and a happy life.