In this video we will learn how to use font awesome together with so epic.
For those of you who never cared about fantasy.
This is one of the most popular item fonts on the Web.
These icons are used by hundreds and even thousands of Web sites.
Traditional way of including the font awesome into your Web site is to add a CDM link inside the head.
One of the students asked me recently if it's possible to install on post some as NPM package and work
with it the same way as it has other dependencies.
The answer is yes and in this video I will show you how in the latest version of fun awesome they introduced
SPG javascript framework using this framework is the recommended way to integrate font.
Awesome.
It is epic.
We need to install four different packages.
Package fun.
Awesome.
That is veggie that corn provides the core functionality of SPG javascript framework.
The other three NBN packages include font awesome icons.
Now we need to go to the editor and import this packages I will import them inside index not J S I will
import from awesome that SPG that core
library object allows us to specify which icons he wants to use we will use.
Don't object to replace any existing I fix these SPG as I already said we don't have to import all possible
icons from fun awesome.
We can specify only those icons which we need in our project I will import on one icon for now which
is f a spinner
and I will add this icon to the library
I am important on the one package which contains solid SPG icons because I don't need the other two
packages.
Obviously if you need an icon from a regular SPG icons or like icons you would need to import those
packages as well.
Now we can end this icon to our page.
I didn't go to the page template and here I will add.
I am specifying three classes here f a s means that we want to use an icon from front or some solid
items at A Dash spinner specifies the name of the icon and F A Dash spin fails the browser that this
icon should rotate.
There are five thousand different icons included in font awesome library and more than 1000 of them
is free of charge.
By the way we can still use IBEX in each demo.
Fun awesome library will replace this text these SPG icons but for this to happen we need to add one
more line to our javascript code.
I will go to index J S and here you remember the imported DOM object.
Now I will use it.
Don't object as watch method and you find what this method than this method will replace any existing
IBEX vs SPG.
What's more it will set up an observer to continue doing this.
If it don't changes for example if B generate some 1000 icons dynamically and add them later to the
document object model they will also be replaced by assuaging.
Now let's go to the terminal and run as a process
and I will start the application.
Let's go to the browser and have a look at the new launching icon.
And you see this a lot in icon right here in the top left corner.
In this video if I've learned how to use one awesome together it's an epic.