At this point we already have a configurations for both single page applications and multiple page applications
as a result of our webpage build.
We have demo files is all the assets included in the case of a single page application.
We have only one HMO filed in the case of a multiple page application.
We have several HMO files each file corresponds to a page on our website.
However usually people don't just put HMO files somewhere on the internet when they want to publish
their Web site.
Well sometimes they do but in most cases people create some kind of a backend or a web server in order
to serve the content to the users.
In this section we will learn how to create such a back end and use it for our application.
It doesn't matter which technology to use while creating such a backhand you can use no GSM BHP Python
Ruby Java and any other technology of your choice.
In this course we will use energy as an expert as James framework.
So let's get started.