In this video we'll integrate express.js into our single page application.
What we'll do now is create a simple web server using Node.js and Express.js framework.
which will show some dummy content in the browser
whenever user loads our web application. Let's create a file called server.js inside our src folder.
In this file we'll put our backend code.
First we need to require Express.
Now we need to create an instance of an express.
I will call the variable app.
What we need to do now, is to create a route on which our application will react.
I will specify a simple home page route which is a slash. And as a second argument,
I will specify a function.
And this function will be called every time an express application gets a request to this route.
Inside this function
we will send some dummy content back to the browser.
We will use res variable which is an instance of response object, and call a method send on it.
We will pass some dummy content as an argument to this method.
Now we need to start our server and make it listen for some port, so the application can actually be
running and listening to incoming connections.
For this we will use our app instance and we will call a method
listen here.
We need to specify a port on which
this web application will be listening for new requests.
I will specify port 3000 and as a second argument we can specify a function. And this function
will be invoked when the application starts.
We can output some information into the console when application starts.
So I will just write "Application is running
on http://localhost:3000".
This will be enough.
What we need to do now is we need to install express.
So in the terminal I'm typing npm install express --save.
In order to conveniently run our server, let's add a new script our package.json. I'm going to the package.json
and I'm looking here for the scripts. Here they are.
So I will just add the new script here. I will name it start.
And I'll simply write here something like 'node src/server.js'. This will start our
server. Now let's run our new script into the terminal.
And it says that our application is running on http://localhost:3000. Let's check it in the
browser. I'm going to the browser and pasting  this link.
Yeah.
And now we have some dummy content in the browser.
It seems that our Express application works! In this video
we have successfully created a simple backend using Node.js and express.js framework that displays
some dummy content when we visit our website in the browser. In the next video
we will learn how to display our own html page instead of a plain text there.