In the previous video we have successfully created a simple backend using Node.js and Express.js framework
that displays some dummy content when we visit our web page in the browser.
In this video we will modify our backend in order to display our own html page instead of a plain
text there.
First we need to replace dummy content that we have now with our html page that we created before.
For this,
we will read the contents of our html file into a string and then send this string to the browser.
Let's do it.
First we need to get an absolute path to our index.html.
For this we will use already familiar Node module which is called path.
We already used it before when we needed to specify an absolute path to our output file in the webpack
configuration. I will remove this for now and instead I will get the path to html file.
equals path.resolve...
And here as a first argument we will specify __dirname, which is our current directory, and as a second argument
will specify relative path to our index.html.
This path is relative to our current directory.
So now we need to import path node module at the beginning of the file.
We don't need to install it via the NPM because path is a built in module
inside
Node.js.
Now when we know path to the index.html, we need to read its contents into a variable. For this we
will use another built in module which is called fs.
readFileSync method reads the contents of the file synchronously and returns the content of the
file.
As a first argument we will specify path to html file,
and as a second argument we need to specify encoding which in our case is UTF 8.
This means that the contents of the file is stored in Unicode.
Now we need to send this content to the browser and we'll use already familiar method send on the
response object.
And we'll send content from
html file.
Let's now rebuild our application and check what we have in the browser.
Now we need to start our application.
And I will open it in the browser.
OK.
We got reference error.
"fs is not defined" because we forgot to import it.
Let's import it here. And now we need to rebuild our application again.
And start it. I'm going to the browser again, reload this page, and now we got nothing.
We've got an empty page here without any content.
Let's investigate why it doesn't work.
First, let's view the html source of our page.
Well the source of the page is html.
And if you look closely you will notice that it is our html.
Here is our bundle.js
and here is our styles.css. So why do we have an empty page?
Let's go to the browser console.
It turns out that we have a bunch of errors.
Browser complains that it cannot load our css and JavaScript.
That's because we did not teach express how to load our css or JavaScript.
We just told express that every time it gets a request to the home URL, which is this slash here,
it needs to send the content of html file back to the browser. And express does it correctly.
It sends html content back to a browser.
We have seen it right now.
But in that html there are links to css and JavaScript. And when Express gets a request for css
file, it doesn't know what to do with this request.
We simply did not tell express yet what it should do when it gets a request to a css file. In the next
video,
we will teach express how to handle static files.