In the previous video we learned how to display our own html page when we get a request to the
home page url
But we did not teach express how to handle requests to static files like css.
Let us teach express how to handle static files.
Now basically what we need to do is just send the contents of this css file back to the browser every
time we get a request for this css file.
In fact we need to do that for all static files.
We have Javascript, css, images, fonts, and so on.
For this we will create a separate route specifically designed to handle static files.
As you remember, all our static files are located in the dist folder. And whenever we get a request for
a static file, we will just take this file from our dist folder and send it back.
We will define a separate url for all our static files
And we will use Express.static method to serve static files.
We would need to specify an absolute path to our dist folder.
path.resolve, __dirname, and relative path to the dist folder.
Now all requests from urls that start with slash static will go directly to our dist folder.
What we need to do is to include slash static in all our static files inside the index.html.
As you can see URLs to our javascript and css files don't include static yet but we don't need to add
static manually to all those links. We can just change the publicPath option inside our webpack configuration
and / static.
will be added automatically to all our generated assets.
So I'm going to our production configuration now. And here
We just need to change public path. Let's now check our browser.
But before that you would need to rebuild our application.
It's done and now I need to start the application.
Let's go to the browser now and check what is there.
I am refreshing  my page and now you see our application is working again.
If I click on the button, the red text appears. Great! Now webpack knows how to handle static files and
our small Web site works perfectly.
In this video we have learned how to handle static files via Express framework.