In this video we will learn how to integrate express.js framework into a multiple page application.
It is very similar to what we did with a single page application.
But now we need to handle several pages. In this video we will be using code from the Section 6
where we created webpack configuration for a multiple page application. So don't be surprised when you see hello-world.js
and kiwi.js here instead of index .JS file.
Let's go through some of the files we'll use in this video.
First let's have a look at the hello world.js.
You should be already familiar with this file.
The only thing here is that we need to remove the line about React.
We don't need this line anymore.
Now let's have a look at kiwi.js file.
We have the same line about React here, and we also don't need it here as well.
We also have server.JS file. We will be using the same code as we did when we talked about single page
applications. But now we need to handle two pages instead of one.
So we need to create two routes instead of one.
First I will change the URL of our existing route to be hello world.
And I will also change the path to html file to relate to
hello world.html.
Now I will just copy this route and adjust it
first
I will change the url to be /kiwi/ and then I will adjust our path to html file to point to the
to kiwi.html page.
we have already installed express.js in the previous videos.
So here I'll skip this step and that's all we need to do.
Let's check now how it works in the browser.
But first let's build our application.
It was a typo there.
Now I need to start the application. npm start.
It says that application is running on port 3000.
So let's go to our browser. and I'll paste a URL in the navigation bar which will be
http://localhost:3000/hello-world/
and now we get our hello world page here. And it works perfectly.
And if I change route to be /kiwi/,
it will go to our kiwi page.
It seems everything looks really good. In this video
we have successfully learned how to handle multiple pages with Express framework.