Hi guys and girls! I hope you're having a wonderful day today.
My name is Viktor and my goal is to help you understand stuff. In this course
my goal is to help you understand Webpack,
its main features, and how you can use it in your projects.
We will be talking about Webpack 4 in this course, but before going further let me first introduce myself.
I am a Senior Software Engineer specializing in JavaScript and various technologies around it.
I am creating web applications for 12 years and during this years I have learned a lot of useful stuff.
Now I want to share my knowledge with you.
Now when you already know a bit about me, let me walk you through the structure of this course.
At the beginning we'll create a small application with only 2 JavaScript files.
This application will serve us as a model on which we can apply different Webpack features and see how we can
handle real world use cases. Then we will create a very basic webpack configuration for our application.
Then we will have a look at loaders and learn how to handle CSS, SASS, images, and other file types using
webpack.
We will also see how we can use latest cutting edge javascript features in our applications even though
they are not implemented in all major browsers yet.
After that we'll have a look at Webpack plugins and learn how we can extract all our CSS into a separate bundle.
We will also learn how Webpack helps us with browser caching and how we can generate HTML files automatically
with all the assets we need. Then we'll talk about differences between production and development builds
and see how we can optimize our webpack configurations. Then we'll talk about multi page applications and
code splitting in general. In the last section
we will learn how to integrate express JS framework both for single page applications and for multiple
page applications.
It seems we have a lot to cover here.
So let's start this wonderful journey together.