Let's talk about what you need in order to succeed in this course.
First you would need a computer or tablet or any other device capable of playing these videos.
But ideally you would need a computer or a laptop on beach you can follow these videos and repeat all
the actions that we are doing here.
You must know basics of JavaScript. JavaScript is a must here because we will do a lot of JavaScript
in this course.
We will not do anything complex here, but at least you must know basics. You must know basics of HTML.
Although we would have only a couple of HTML files here,
it will be very beneficial to you.
By the way HTML is very easy to learn.
I know several people who learned the basics of it during a couple of days.
This is all about musts.
With this you'll be able to understand most of the things in this course. Everything else is nice to have.
Those things will be needed if you want to understand webpack deeply and learn faster. I really encourage
you to repeat on your computer
everything that we will do in this course.
This is the best way to learn and I can really recommend it. You would need a browser. Chrome, Firefox,
Safari, Edge, or any other browser that can execute javascript.
By the way, Internet Explorer is also a browser.
You would need a text editor. You can use any text editor of your choice. Visual Studio Code, Atom,
Webstorm would be examples of popular editors nowadays.
In this videos I will be using Atom. You can download it on this Website,
if you decide to use it as well. If you want to follow the videos and repeat everything that we are doing
here, you would need to install NodeJS. You can download it from this website. NodeJS is a javascript environment
that can execute javascript code on the backend.
We will use NodeJS in order to run webpack in the terminal. And the last,
not being afraid of command line, or terminal. You shouldn't be afraid of these things.
Linux and Mac users have terminal installed by default in their systems and Windows users can use cmder
which is a console emulator for Windows.
You can download cmder from this website.
Basically that's all that you need in this course.
Enough introduction.
Let's proceed now to the core of the course.