In this video people talk about mode option.
Remember in our back configuration if a special option called mode this option enables certain things
in optimizations for production deals and development bills.
By the way the mode option became available starting from.
For earlier versions of required much more configuration in order to get the same results in the beginning
of this course we have set this option to num.
It means that we don't want any kind of built in optimizations.
Now it's time to change the setting.
We can put here three different entities non development or production.
Let's add more option two different variables and compare what happens with our bundles.
First let's set it to production
production mode enables quite a long list of different plugins including some plugin.
If you want to see the full list of plugins you can go to the official web backed documentation to this
page
and here you can find the full list of plugins.
The mode option also sets process and not and variable to production.
We can use this variable in our code to check if they are in production mode or in development mode.
Let's go to index not J S now and see how it works
I will add a little bit of code here that will check note and variable
note and variable equal to production legal output to the console.
Production mode.
And if this variable equals 2 development we will output to the console development mode.
Production and development mode also handle errors difference.
Let's make some intentional error here.
Real cold metal that does not exist.
Now we need to run our build in the terminal.
Let's go to the browser and look into the browser console.
I can copy the full POS to our index HDMI out.
And paste it into the browser
in the browser console.
We can see that we are in production mode and that we had an error because all our javascript code is
bundled inside the one file and modified.
We just see that this error comes somewhere from bundle the J S from line 1 if we click on this line
then we'll go to that magnified version of our code.
It is very hard to understand any sum here.
Now let's change the mode auction to development and run our event.
Again
now we need to go to the terminal and front our built
so let's go to the browser and check the page one more time.
Now we can see that we are in development mode and that we have an error coming specifically from index
J S from line 16 if I click on this line.
I will go to the readable version of our source files does this specific line end here.
I can see that the accounting method does not exist.
This is already much better.
This works because development mode uses source maps by default.
In this video we have seen how we can use smart option for optimizing our production and development
yields.