In the previous video video and how we can use mullet auction in order to change what behavior for production
and development builds.
First we changed the mold auction indirect configuration to production and then to development following
this practice we would need to set mold auction to development while developing our application and
change it to production.
Every time we want to deploy the application this is not very convenient.
In this video I will show you how to manage effectively different configurations for production and
development deals we can create two separate configuration files one for production builds and one for
development builds.
So we name our PAC not contact the J.
S to let the production the conflict that J S
and you also create one more file.
What that that the quantity the J.
S
or now I do copy everything from the production configuration into this file
however we need to adjust these configurations.
Let's adjust our production configuration really to set mold auction to production.
We can safely remove to support in the cost in production mode.
This plugin is included by default you can also remove a set of plugin from imports everyone else in
this file is suitable for production.
So our production configuration was built.
Now let's go to the development configuration and remove everything that you don't need.
When you put change multifunction to development and it is a lot of development.
So now we need to remove content from here because we don't need to handle other occasions during development.
We can also remove our surplus from London's every because they don't need to modify our code during
development and also remove it from imports.
Here you don't need to extract all our sea assets into a separate file as well.
So I will remove this USS extra one from here.
And from here you also need to replace this one in the rules and I will replace this style order
all this changes should make our development faster.
It won't notice any difference in our small application but in bigger applications the difference can
be significant.
Since we now get two different configuration files it also need the ability to run them separately.
This can be easily done using NPM scripts so I'll go to the package Jason File
and here we have our streets and for now the arbitration panel in one script which is built I will continue
using this script for production purposes.
So here I need to specify our production configuration
and I'll create one more script
but here I will specify the development configuration.
Now let's check these two NPM scripts.
I don't go to the terminal
production but it works fine.
Let's now check development build
development build.
Also works fine.
So in this video we have created two separate configurations for production and development.
At this point we have fully fledged configurations specifically targeting single page application.