In the previous video we created two separate configurations for development and production builds.
We did it because our development build should have another settings that the production build, in order
to work faster. While developing new features,
we want to spend as little time as we can waiting for our code to build.
Ideally we want to see our changes in the browser instantly, even without rebuilding stuff.
I have a good news for you guys and girls.
We can make it happen!
And in this video I'll show you how. We will need to install webpack-dev-server NPM package.
It provides all the things we need. So we are going to the terminal now and installing webpack-dev-server.
Now we need to specify options for the dev server.
We can just go to our development config and add a couple of lines there.
I'm going to webpack.dev.config.
And here I will add a new option called devServer.
This is an object and inside we need to specify three options. First one is content base,
and it should point to our dist folder as an absolute path.
So I can copy the absolute path from here and paste it here. It will be the same.
The next option is index and here we need to specify the name of the index.html file.
So in our case its index.html. And the third option will be port on which this webpack-dev-server will
be running. I will put 9000 here.
Now we need to change our NPM script for development build so it will use webpack-dev-server.
I will go to the package.json
and here I can see our development script. So I will replace it with a webpack-dev-server.
Here instead of webpack I will write webpack-dev-server
and at the end of this command I will write --hot. And that's it!
Let's run our development build and see what happens.
I will go to the terminal and run npm run dev.
So the build is ready. And webpack said that project is running at the http://localhost:9000. So I will
open this URL in the browser.
And here we have our page.
I will now put my browser and my editor on one screen side by side.
Now let's change something in the index.js.
I will create a second page here.
Just copy this two lines
And change the variable into heading2.
So I have created the second heading now.
And the magic begins.
I am saving this file and...
you saw it!?
We got an updated version in our browser instantly! without running webpack in the terminal!
Pure magic!
We can do the same with our css.
I will go to the hello-world-button styles and change the color of the button.
Now I'm inside hello-world-button.scss file, and I want to change button background color
to red.
And I am saving the file...
You saw it again!? It works instantly! In this video we have learned how to get our changes in the browser without
manually running webpack, and also  have seen some magic.