Until this moment we have used webpack in order to take all our modules and put them together into
a single bundle js file.
As a result this bundle JS contains all our javascript code.
This approach is widely used when there is a need to create a single page application.
But this is not the only usage of Webpack. In some projects
we need to have more than one html page. Especially if these pages are rendered on the server side
Then most probably server sends different pages to the browser depending on the url that you write
in the navigation bar.
Like for example if we go to our Hello World page, then we see our hello world button.
And if we go to a separate kiwi page, we'll see our Kiwi image.
Remember? we imported this image early at the beginning of this course.
By the way, this two pages may also have something in common.
For example lodash library.
Then we need to find out how to handle this common dependencies as well.
In this section we'll learn how to split our javascript code into multiple bundles and create multiple
html files for different pages of our website.