Let's imagine that our Website should consist of two pages.
One is a hello world page which we already have.
And the second one is kiwi page which we have just seen in the previous video.
Our second page would need a new component which would add a kiwi image to the page. In this video
we will create this component.
All it will do is just add our kiwi image to the body DOM element.
We will create a new folder inside the components folder for our new component.
I will name this folder kiwi image
And I will move the kiwi image that we already have to this new folder.
Now we need to create the component itself.
So I will create a new JavaScript file
I will also name it kiwi image dot js.
And inside this file we will create our kiwi image component. So I will create a new class.
And this class will have only one function inside which is render.
Inside this function we will create our image element and then add it to the body DOM element.
I will add src to this image element. It should be a path to our kiwi image.
For this we would need to import our image into this file.
And now I can use Kiwi as an src.
We would also put an alt attribute here.
And I will add a class , css class to this element, because we would need to do some styling.
Now we already have our image element.
What we need to do now is to add this element to the existing body DOM element of our page.
OK it seems we are done now.
We need to export our kiwi image class from this file.
So later we can import it inside our new Page
I missed a space here.
This component who also has some css.
So we will add it as well. Inside our Kiwi image folder
I will create yet another file which he'll be called
kiwi image dot scss.
And inside this file I will add some simple css to our image.
I will specify display block and I will specify some specific width for our component, so it wouldn't be very
big.
Like for example 400 pixels and also I will put height auto.
Now we need to import this css file inside the main component file, so I will go to
kiwi image dot js. And right  below the importing our image
i will import css as well.
It seems our component is ready now. In the next video we will create a page that will use this component.