In this video we will learn how to create two separate javascript bundles instead of one. In our future videos
we'll include the first javascript bundle on the hello world page and the second javascript bundle on
kiwi page.
So let's create our second page.
We will reuse our kiwi image component that we created in the previous video.
So now I will create a new script file for our kiwi page
and I'll name it
kiwi.js.
This Javascript file to present our second page,
kiwi page.
It will look almost the same as the hello world page, but instead with the kiwi component inside.
So let's create it.
First let's import heading,
because on this page we will also have heading.
And now let's create an instance of our heading component and render it.
Besides heading
we also need our kiwi image component which we just created in the previous video.
So let's import it.
okay.
And now we need to instantiate it and to render it.
cool.
It seems this page is ready.
Let's also rename our existing index.js file into hello-world.js.
Now we have two different JavaScript files that basically represent two different entry points that
should be included inside two different html pages.
Let's tell webpack to create two separate javascript bundles out of these two files.
We need to go to
webpack.production config.js.
And here we need to change something in our entry.
Basically we'll split this one file into two files so what we need to do is to replace this string with
a javascript object. Inside this object we will have two properties.
First one would be hello world
and it will point to the hello world file.
And the second property would be named kiwi.
And it will point to our kiwi.js file that he just created.
Since we have two entry points instead of one,
now we need to specify somehow that their names should be different.
With current configuration both of them will be named bundle.js.
Of course they will have content hash inside but it would be nice if we name it something different
that bundle.js. For example,
hello-world.js and kiwi.js.
So for this we just need to replace this bundle with a [name]. Like this.
So webpack will just take the name of the property from the entry point configuration option and put it
here.
And for the second file it will take other property and put it here.
By the way we can do the same trick for css files.
We just need to go to the mini-css-extract-plugin configuration and change the file name to
something very similar.
So we will also use [name] there.
Let's go to our configuration and change... inside this string we will change styles to be [name].
So let's run webpack now and check what we get after that in our dist folder.
Let's go to the terminal
And run npm run build.
it seems our build is done.
Let's go to our editor now and have a look at our dist folder.
We see that now we have two different JavaScript files inside our dist folder. One is called hello-world..js
and another one called kiwi..js.
And we also have two different css files. In this video
we have learned how to split our code into multiple bundles.