In the previous video we have learned how to split our javascript code into multiple bundles.
But if you run webpack now, you will see that all our bundles are included inside one html file which
is index.html.
Let's check it. I run my build now. I will go to the editor and check our dist folder.
And here we have index.html.
And if I open it, I clearly see that all our javascript bundles
hello-world.js
and kiwi.js are included inside this single file. And the same with css files. Both of them are here.
However, we would need to generate two different html pages if we need proper multiple page
application. One page would be Hello World page and the other one would be kiwi html page.
In this video we will learn how we can generate multiple html files and include different bundles inside different
html files.
Let's go to our Webpack production config.
And check our configuration for the  HtmlWebpackPlugin.
I'm going down to the plugins array and I see here
Our HtmlWebpackPlugin.
But if we want to generate 2 html files, we need to include HtmlWebpackPlugin twice in the
plugins array.
So I will add a second instance of this plugin here.
Now we need to differentiate between the two instances of HtmlWebpackPlugin.
The best solution here is to provide different file names. Our first instance would have a file name
hello-world.html.
And title would be hello world, description would still be hello world, and template...
We are using an index.hbs here, but I think we need to rename it, because it's no longer index anymore.
So I will just rename it to something more generic like page-template.hbs.
And here
I will also use page-template.hbs.
So now we need to adjust to the second instance of HtmlWebpackPlugin.
Also provide a filename
here.
And it will be kiwi.html, and Title I will change to "Kiwi". And the same with description. I will
also use here
page-template.hbs as a template.
Cool.
But now how do we know which bundles to include in this file name, in the hello-world.html,
and which bundles include inside kiwi.html?
HtmlWebpackPlugin has a special option here called chunks where we can specify which bundles
exactly we would need to include inside this html page.
So I will add these configuration options here. Chunks and this is an array, so actually you can specify
multiple chunks, not only one. But in our case we need the only one chunk now which is hello world
n this example, and here it would be kiwi.
Chunk names are specified here inside the entry point array, actually entry point object, sorry.
So let's run webpack now and check how many html files we have afterwards.
Let's go to our editor and check our dist folder one more time.
And if we look inside dist folder we can see that now we have two html files in our dist folder.
One html file is kiwi.html, and the other file is hello-world.html. Let's have a look at
hello-world.html. And here we can see that we have only one css file included here which is
hello-world..css and only one JavaScript file included which is hello-world..js
If we have a look inside our kiwi.html file, we can see that here we also have only one
css file an only one JavaScript file. So in this video we have learned how we can generate multiple
html files and include different bundles inside different html files.