In this video we're going to learn how to handle common dependencies between multiple bundles.
Earlier we have seen how we can split our javascript code between multiple bundles and how to generate
multiple html pages. But sometimes all the website pages depend on some common library or a framework.
Let's have a look at a simple example.
Imagine that you want to show the name of the current page in the heading.
For this you would need to modify our heading component.
I'll go to the heading component JavaScript file
and I'll modify something in our H1 element. I will add here the page name.
For this I would introduce a page name variable.
I also put it in the quotes.
Since we are using page name variable here,
we would need to add it as an argument,
to the render function. Since we added an argument to the render function,
we need to change all the invocations of it.
We have two places where we use heading component. In the hello-world.js and kiwi.js.
First I will go to the
hello-world.js.
Here we are using our heading component and invoking the render function.
So we now have one argument that we need to pass, and I will pass the name of the page which is
hello world.
In order to make the first letter of the page name uppercase,
we will use lodash. So I will use the lodash function named upperFirst.
This function will make the first letter of our hello world string a capital letter.
This is not the best solution for make an uppercase strings but it suits our example ideally. In order
to use lodash,
we would need to import it.
And we also need to install it.
So I will go to the terminal
and I will install lodash.
OK lodash is installed.
Then we need to go back to our editor and basically do the same for the kiwi.js page.
So what I will do here, I will pass the name of the page
which is capitalized. It will be kiwi. And we also need to import lodash library from here as well.
cool.
So now we need to run webpack.
Now if you have a look at the files webpack has generated for us,
we can notice that our javascript bundles became pretty big.
kiwi.js
takes 70 kilobytes, and hello-world.js also takes 70 kilobytes. But 70 kilobytes is too much for
10 or 15 lines of code that we have in those modules.
So what happened?
Remember we included lodash at the beginning of the file?
It seems webpack has included lodash in both javascript bundles and lodash
is quite big.
Now every time we change something in kiwi.js the new 70 kilobyte bundle will be generated. And our
users will need to download it again.
Sounds not very nice,
right?
Webpack has a mechanism that can extract lodash and any other common dependencies into its own bundle.
Let's see how we can do it.
We need to go to webpack.production.config.js
and add a new configuration option here right below the mode.
It is called optimization.
It is an object and inside it we can specify another option which is called splitChunks.
And inside
we need to specify yet another option
which is called chunks, and here specify the value "all".
So after we have added this new configuration option let's run webpack and see what happens.
If we have a look into webpack
output,
we'll see that both hello-world.js and kiwi.js
consume less than 2 kilobytes now. Which is pretty nice! And we have now third javascript bundle
which is called vendors~hello-world~kiwi..js which consumes around 70 kilobytes. So in this bundle
we have lodash.
This third bundle will be cached separately and now our users don't need to download it when we change something
in kiwi.js
or hello-world.js. Since we have a new bundle, how webpack knows where to include it?
Will all html pages include it by default?
The answer is we should specifically tell webpack to include it for every html page that needs it.
In our case both our pages need this bundle.
So now let's go back to our editor to our webpack  configuration and scroll down to the HtmlWebpackPlugin.
And here remember we included chunks.
So now every our html page would need two chunks instead of one.
And the second chunk would be this common chunk, common bundle, which includes lodash library.
Which is called
vendors~hello-world~kiwi.
You would need to specify the same chunk name for our kiwi.html file as well.
Now let's run webpack once more and check how it works in the browser.
Let's go to our Web browser now.
But first I would need to copy the path to our html file. So I will go to the editor to the dist folder
and I will copy the path
to hello-world.html file, and go to the browser again. I paste it, and now we see our page, Hello World
page, which is working.
So let's check another one.
I'll copy the path to the kiwi.html  file and go to the browser again and open it here.
Yes and it also works.
And it says "This is Kiwi  page". As we can see, both our pages work perfectly.
And if we have a look into developer tools, into a network tab, you you'll see that in addition to the
kiwi.js bundle and kiwi.css bundle
we also have a third bundle which is called
vendors~hello-world~kiwi.
This is how we can handle our common dependencies between multiple html pages.
We also can use this mechanism if we want to extract some external dependencies, like React for example,
into a separate bundle.
And if we don't have multiple html files, this may be useful for browser caching as well.
Every time we change something in our javascript code, users would have to download onto our javascript
code, without all external dependencies that haven't been changed. In this video we have learned how
to handle common dependencies between multiple pages.