In the previous video we have learned how to extract common dependencies into a separate bundle.
We used lodash in our example and webpack has put it into a separate bundle.
Let's try to do the same
with React now.
But first let's remove lodash and remove our upperFirst function. Because we don't include lodash anymore.
I will do the same in kiwi.js
okay.
We are done.
So now let's import  React.
I will do the same in kiwi.js.
Now we would need to install react.
Let's do it.
Let's go to our terminal and install React.
Now let's run our build in the terminal and see what happens.
If we look at the bundles that webpack generated,
we'll see that there is no additional javascript bundle here.
There are only Kiwi..js
and
hello-world..js.
And
that's it.
But previously we had an additional bundle including lodash dependency.
So what happened?
You see, by default webpack extracts common dependencies only when they exceed 30 kilobytes before minification.
It worked with lodash because lodash is more than 30 kilobytes. But it doesn't work with React, because
React is less than 30 kilobytes.
So what do we do
if we want to extract react into a separate bundle? There is a way to specify custom configuration options
for splitting chunks.
In our example let's make the threshold size smaller, let's say, 10 kilobytes.
For this we would need to go to our editor, to the webpack production configuration, and add a new option
inside optimisation option. This option is called minsize. And we will specify 10 thousand here.
We can also specify another name delimiter for this additional bundle.
So we'll have a new option here which is called automatic name delimiter.
And we will put an underscore there. Let's run our build now and see if anything changes.
I will scroll up.
We can see that now we have a separate bundle named
vendors_hello-world_kiwi..js. It is only 7 kilobytes in size and uses underscores as file
delimiters.
What's important,
Our kiwi.js
and hello-world.js bundles are less than two kilobytes each.
In this video we have learned how to set custom criteria for extracting common dependencies.