In the previous videos we have learned how to set up production configuration for multiple page applications.
As a result after every build we are getting several html files for several web pages.
Previously in this course we have seen how convenient it is to get fast feedback about our code changes.
In this video we will learn how to setup development configuration for multiple page applications.
Let's go to the webpack.dev.config.js
and change some things there. First we need to put two entry points instead
of one. So I will replace this string with a javascript object which we have already seen.
And here
We'll have only two properties.
hello-world
which will point to our.
hello-world.js file,
and kiwi, which will point to our kiwi.js file.
Since we have two entry points now we need to adjust our output configuration.
And I will just add here [name] .
So now we have output file name
[name].bundle.js.
Now we need to add a second HtmlWebpackPlugin
to the list of plugins. Because we have two html pages now.
First I will modify our first entry because we need to change something here.
We need to specify file name which will be hello-world.html, and we also need to specify chunks
which is an array.
And here we will need a hello-world chunk.
If you remember the chunk webpack takes from these entry points.
And here we need to replace our index.hbs with page-template.hbs  because we renamed it before.
So now we'll also need a second
HtmlWebpackPlugin here.
This one would relate to our kiwi page.
So I will rename this hello-world to the kiwi
And we will also need kiwi chunk.
I'll replace title as well as a description.
And I believe template is the same because both our html files are using the same page template.
And basically that's all we need to do.
We don't need to split common dependencies into a separate bundle because this is the development build
and all we care about is the speed of the build. Let's run our development build in the terminal and
have a look at what we have in the browser
Webpack tells us that project is running at a http://localhost:9000 so I'll copy
this url and go to our browser now and I will paste this url into the navigation bar.
And as we can see there is nothing at our main url now, but we can open different pages using
different urls. First I will go to our hello-world.html page.
I will add slash hello-world.html.
This is totally the same as the name of our html page that we generated in the dist folder.
And now we can see that our hello-world page works perfectly. When they click on the button, we see the
red text appearing.  So let's now check our kiwi page. I will replace hello-world.html with
kiwi.html.
And now we can see that our kiwi page also works. In this video
we have learned how to set up development configuration for multiple page applications. At this point
we have fully fledged webpack configurations for both production and development environments specifically
targeting multiple page applications.