In this section we are going to learn about Webpack plugins. A plugin is a Javascript library that adds functionality
to the Webpack itself.
Plugins can do everything that loaders cannot do.
We use loaders for example when we need to import different files. When we need to import css files,
we use css loader, and when we need to import xml files, we use xml loader.
But what if you need to do something else than importing a new type of file? With plugins
we can do much more.
We can define global constants across the whole project.
We can minify our resulting bundle so it consumes less space and is faster to download.
We can also generate new files, other than the bundle.js.
Webpack itself is built on the same plugin system that we can use in our Webpack configuration.
In the next video
We will have a look at a plugin that can minify our resulting bundle.