In this section we have learned about wetback plugins.
First we have learned how we can make our resulting bundles smaller,
so it is faster to download. Then we extracted all our css into a separate css bundle.
Also we learned how we can generate HTML files automatically during the build process. We used only several
plugins
in this course.
I believe they are the most important ones, but you have seen that it is very easy to include a new plugin
into your webpack configuration.
Here is the list of official webpack plugins, and if you need some plugin from this list just click on the
link and go to the respective plugin page.
There you can see how to configure this particular plugin for your project.
In addition to that there are a lot of third party Webpack plugins that you can use. So you will never get
bored with this stuff!