In this video we're going to learn how to minify our javascript bundle.
But first let's understand why we need to minify it.
We are striving for the best experience for our customers. We want our websites to load fast.
If your customers are using your website on mobile then the website performance is crucial for them.
If you make the size of the javascript file smaller than the whole Website will load faster.
What's more, it will consume less Internet traffic.
Now let's have a look at our current bundle size. Our bundle now is inside dist folder and I will right click
on it, and open it in the file manager.
And here I can get more information about this file.
And here we can see that our file currently consumes 21 kilobytes of disk space.
Let's figure out how to make it smaller. In order to make our bundle smaller,
I will need to add a special plugin to webpack. This plugin is called TerserPlugin.
So let's add TerserPlugin and see if the bundle size changes
after that. I will go to the webpack.config.JS file and add a new section there which is called plugins.
This is a javascript array. You can put here as many plugins as you want.
For now I will put here only one plugin.
Pay attention that I am creating a new instance of TerserPlugin here.
Now we need to import TerserPlugin at the beginning of the file.
Since we are using a new plugin here,
We need to install it.
So I will go to my terminal and install this plugin.
All webpack plugins should be installed
with  --save-dev option, to indicate that they are used as development dependencies.
Webpack plugin is a development dependency because we need it only during the build process.
If we use --save option,
without the dev part, then it would be considered a production dependency. Production dependencies are
required when we publish our project to production servers.
However we usually don't need webpack plugins on production servers.
That's why it's a development dependency.
Now let's run webpack and check the bundle size one more time.
the build is done.
Let's go to the editor again and look how many kilobytes our bundle.js file consumes now.
So I open it in the file manager, and here I will look again at the information.
And here I can see that it now consumes only 7 kilobytes.
So we have just made our bundle size smaller.
As a side note I would like to mention here that using TerserPlugin is a new way of minifying your javascript bundles.
Earlier Webpack was using  Uglifyjsplugin for the same purposes.
You can still use Uglifyjsplugin and get the same results.
However using TerserPlugin is the recommended way nowadays.
You can still see Uglifyjsplugin in the other videos of this course
until I update all the lectures.