In this video we're going to learn how to extract our CSS into a separate file.
This video consists of two parts.
This is part one. Some time ago we learned how to import css inside our JavaScript files.
We did it using CSS loader and style loader.
As you can see all our styles are inside the style tag, right here.
Even though this is fine for development purposes, this is not good for production.
Using this approach
all our styles are bundled together with our javascript code inside a single file called bundle.js.
Styles are dynamically added to the Document Object Model
by javascript during runtime. However there is one problem with this approach. Our bundle file will become
very big after some time. And big files need more time to load. What we can do here, is extract all our
css into a separate file that will be generated alongside our javascript bundle.
This way we can have two bundles instead of one.
Why is it better than having one bundle?
First this will make the size of our javascript bundle much smaller so it will be faster to download.
And second this will allow us to load several files in parallel making overall experience even better.
Let's do something with our styles.
We need to add a new plugin inside our webpack configuration.
The name of this plugin is MiniCssExtractPlugin.
So I'm going to add a new plugin to the list of plugins.
This will extract our css into a separate file. And we can even specify the name of this file.
Now we need to modify our rules for CSS and SASS in order to use MiniCssExtractPlugin.
First I will change the rule for css.
I need to replace style loader
with MiniCssExtractPlugin.loader.
Now I need to do the same
with the sass rule.
We also need to import this plugin at the beginning of the file.
Since we are using a new plugin here, we need to install it.
Now let's run the build process and check if we get something new in the dist folder.
As you can see we are having one additional file inside the dist folder and this file is called
styles.css.
Now we need to include this file inside our html markup.
Let's check if everything works in the browser.
As you can see our styles work as before.
However,
now we don't have any styles inside our style tag.
Actually there is no style tag at all.
Instead we're having these styles inside an external file.