So let's go to the text editor and look inside the generated styles.css.
Here is all our css from the whole application.
Currently our application consists only of one component.
Hello world
Button.
Let's create another component
with some styles and check if all the css from both components goes into
styles.css file. We'll create a component named Heading.
So now I will create a Heading directory inside the components directory,
and inside this directory I will create a new
file.
Heading
.js
Let's create a new class for our component.
This class
will have only one method called render.
This method will create an H1 element and insert it into the body element.
I will put some text inside H1.
And I will add this H1 element to the body.
Now we need to export this class.
Okay, our new component is finished.
And what I'd like to do now, is import our styles at the top of the file.
We don't have any styles for this component yet, but we'll create them in a moment.
Let's create a new file for our styles.
I created this file inside the same directory as the javascript file. This file will be very simple.
We'll just set a color of an H1  element.
I will put "gray" here.
It will be enough for this example.
Now let's import our new component inside
index.js.
We need to create an instance of the Heading component and then call the render method.
Let's run the build process and have a look at the dist folder.
I'm going back to my editor and open styles.css
And here we can see that css for both our components is inside.
These styles correspond to the Hello World Button component, and these two lines correspond to the heading component.
In other words MiniCssExtractPlugin extracts all our styles from the application and puts them
inside a single css file under the dist folder.
Now let's check our application in the browser.
I refreshed my page in the browser and we got a new heading here which says " Webpack is awesome",
which is pretty much true. In this video
We learned how to extract our css into a separate file.