In this video we are going to talk about browser caching and how Webpack can help us with that. This time
We'll start with the theory before writing any code. As you might know,
every time your browser loads a website, it downloads all the assets required by this Website.
Each Website is different.
However most of them require some javascript and css in order to work properly.
And some Websites require lots of JavaScript.
Each time the user reloads the page, their browser downloads all those files from the Internet.
This may become an issue, especially if your customers browse your website using mobile devices
with slow internet connection.
Each time they go to a new page they need to wait several minutes until the page is ready.
Fortunately there is a solution to this problem.
And it's called browser caching.
If the file didn't change between the page reloads, your browser can save it in a specific place.
This place is called cache.
When you open this page again browser won't download this file again.
It will take this file from cache.
This technique helps to save lots of time and traffic.
However this may lead to another issue.
What if you fixed a bug on your Website and your javascript file has been changed? If the browser always
takes this file from cache your customers will never get the new version.
Therefore we need a mechanism for updating the cache.
One of the most popular approaches is creating a new file with the new name
each time you make a change. Browsers remember files by name.
Therefore if the name changes browsers will download the new version.
Well it doesn't mean that we need to change the filename manually every time we change our code.
We can do this automatically.
Let's go to the webpack configuration file.
One of the best practices is to add md5 hash to the name of the file. this md5 cache
depends on the contents of the file.
This way back will generate the new filename only if there are some changes inside.
It's easy to explain my example. Imagine you changed something in your css but you didn't touch
your javascript.
In this case webpack will generate the new name for your CSS file but it will use the previous name
for a javascript file, and during the next page reload your customers will download the new CSS file
but they will get the javascript file from cache. In order for this to work, we just need to add [contenthash]
in square brackets to the output file name.
Now let's run webpack in the terminal and check the dist folder
You see, we have two JavaScript files in the dist folder.
One is bundle.JS and another one is bundle dot some strange sequence of characters dot J S.
This sequence of characters is md5 hash and it stays the same
if there were no code changes. Let's run webpack again and have a look at the dist folder
one more time.
I just run webpack and we still have the same JavaScript files in the dist folder.
Let's now change something inside our javascript.
I've added only one line of code here.
Let's run webpack again and have a look at the dist folder.
Now we have 3 JavaScript files in the dist folder.
That's because Webpack generated the new javascript
file with different md5 hash. Now let's remove this line of code. It was needed for demonstration
purposes. By the way
this also works for CSS files.
We just need to add contenthash in square brackets to the
MiniCssExtractPlugin configuration.
Let's run webpack again and have a look at the dist folder.
Now there is another css file in the dist folder, and this css file contains md5 hash
as well.