At the moment our dist folder is quite cluttered, and most of the files inside are redundant.
These are the leftovers from the previous builds.
That's because the names of our bundles contain md5 hash.
This md5 hash is generated based on the contents of the file. Each time you change something inside
any file, it's md5 hash changes as well.
That's why
we are getting new bundles with every code change. In this video
We'll see how we can remove old bundles from the dist folder before generating new bundles.
I bet you already guessed that webpack has a plugin for that.
And you're right.  The name of this plugin is
CleanWebpackPlugin.
So let's add this plugin to the plugins array.
Each time you run the build process CleanWebpackPlugin will clean the output.path folder.
This is the output.path folder.
In our case this is the dist folder.
But what do I mean by cleaning? Every time we run webpack, CleanWebpackPlugin simply removes all the files
from this folder.
This way webpack ensures that it has absolutely clean folder before putting anyone else to it.
We also need to import CleanWebpackPlugin in order to be able to use it.
Since we are using a new plugin here we need to install it.
As you remember our dist folder currently contains 5 different files inside.
So now let's run the build process.
And now the dist folder contains only two files.
That's because CleanWebpackPlugin has removed other files from the dist folder.
By the way
it's possible to clean multiple folders with this plugin.
You just need to provide a couple of options when instantiateing this plugin in the plugins array.
Let's imagine we have one more folder generated by some other tool where you store some additional css
files. I will create this folder now.
And inside the build folder we'll have one css file,
and one subfolder
with another css file.
Lets configure webpack to clean this folder as well.
Clean once before build patterns removes old files before webpack generates the new files.
You can specify an array of the file patterns which you want to remove. All patterns are relative to the webpack
output.path   directory. In our case
this is the dist folder.
This means to remove all the files together with sub directories inside the dist folder
no matter how many nesting levels there are.
This is how clean once before
build patterns looks
by default, if you don't modify it. However if you want to remove the files outside of the dist folder
you should specify an absolute path to the file patterns.
This will remove all the files together
with  subfolders inside the build folder. Let's check how it works.
I'll go to the text editor
And now you can see that the build folder is empty.
This means that webpack removed all the files together with subdirectories from this folder.
So in this video we learned how to use CleanWebpackPlugin in order to keep the folder nice and clean.