In the previous videos we added md5 hash to our bundles and learn how to keep the dist folder
nice and clean.
But did you notice what happened to our html file?
you're right.
Absolutely nothing.
So if I open it now in the browser our application will be broken.
You see there is an empty page here and there are two errors in the browser console.
Do you know why it's broken? If I go to the html file you'll see that the references to our bundles
don't include md5 hash.
This reference doesn't include md5 hash.
And this reference as well doesn't include md5 hash. So in order to fix our small website we
need to change these references.
So now I will just copy the file name from here
and paste it here. I will do the same
with the CSS file.
let's go to the browser and check if this fixed
our website. I will reload the page.
And now you see that our website works again.
So does this mean that we need to change the names of the files manually
after every build?
Come on, we are in the 21st century. Even dishes can be washed automatically
if you put them into a dishwasher.
Of course webpack has a special plugin that updates the names of the files during each build.
This plugin is called html-webpack-plugin and it can also create html file for us. So we don't
have to worry about that.
Let's go to the Webpack configuration and add this plugin to the list of plugins.
Now let's import this plugin at the beginning of the file.
The only thing that's left is to install it
via NPM.
Let's run the build process and have a look at the dist folder.
I will go to the text editor and look inside the dist folder.
it looks like we have a new file inside the dist folder and this file is called index.html.
Webpack
generated this file automatically when we run the build process. This file looks pretty much the same
as our own index.html.
Except that formatting is not so nice.
However there is one more thing we need to adjust. The path to our bundles
still starts with the prefix dist. Since our html file is also located inside the dist folder,
as the bundles themselves, we don't need this prefix anymore, So we need to remove this prefix.
Webpack generates this prefix according to the publicPath option.
And we can change this option right here.
So instead of dist I will leave it empty.
Now let's run the build process again.
I will go back to the text editor and open the index.html file and now I can see that there is
no dist prefix anymore. As you can see
Now we have two html files. one html file is generated by Webpack and located inside the dist folder
and another html file is located in the root directory of our project that we created ourselves.
So let's remove this second file because we don't need it anymore.
He will only use the html file generated by Webpack
Let's open this html file in the browser and check if everything works.
As you can see everything still works even though we are using html file that was generated automatically.
In the next video
You'll learn how to customize some stuff inside this html file.