In the previous video we learned how to generate the html file automatically during each build. In this
video
We are going to learn how to customize this file.
In particular we are going to pass custom options to it. If you look carefully at the generated file, you
will notice that Webpack changed the page title.
Earlier
the title was hello world and now it is Webpack app.
We want our title back and there is a way to get it back.
Let's go to the Webpack configuration.
Here we can pass additional options
to this plugin. For example we can specify a custom title
Actually,
we can customize more things.
We can also specify the name of the generated file and provide additional meta tags. Let's specify
a custom file name.
By the way,
we can also specify a subfolder here.
This tells Webpack to create a subfolder in the dist folder and put the html file inside this subfolder.
Let's provide an additional meta tag.
This tells Webpack to add a description meta tag to the page.
Let's run the build process and check if anything changes.
Let's go back to the text editor.
As you can see now we have a subfolder inside the dist folder and inside this subfolder there is
our html file.
It has our own title which is hello world and our own description which is some description.
Let's leave the filename as it was by default. I will remove the filename from options.
There are more options you can customize.
All these options are listed on the Github page of this plugin.
If you scroll down you will see the list of options
you can customize.
This is a list of options. It's quite big.
By the way you can even provide your own template for the html file.
This way you can fully customize how it looks. In the next video you'll see how you can do it.