In this video we're going to create our own template for generating html files.
First of all we need to decide which template engine we are going to use.
There are plenty of template engines out there. You can use pug, ejs, underscore, handlebars and
so on.
All of them will give you similar results.
Which one to use is just a matter of personal preference.
I like handlebars the most.
So in this course we are going to use handlebars
handlebars is a template engine for javascript that allows you to separate the business logic from presentation.
If you find yourself generating html inside your javascript then you probably need some kind
of template engine.
Let's create our first handlebars template.
We are going to create this template inside the src folder.
hbs is
an extension for handlebars templates. I will copy the html markup from the generated html file
and put it here.
Let's improve formatting
a bit.
We also need to remove the references to the bundles.
Webpack will add these references automatically during the build process.
The names of the generated files will be different each time because we are using md5 hash
in the bundle name.
You can put everything you need inside this handlebars file. Webpack will use it as a template while generating
an html file during the build process.
In our case I will leave the template as it is, but I'll change the title and description in order to
use handlebars
variables.
This is the handlebars variable.
We'll assign this variable in the Webpack configuration.
I will also put the handlebars variable instead of the title.
Now let's tell Webpack to use our template while generating the html file. I will go to the Webpack configuration.
And here you I will pass a new option which is called template.
Here I specified to path to the file that we just created.
We also need to provide the description variable.
It should be specified on the same level as title.
Webpack will take handlebars variables from here and here.
Since we are using a new type of file here,
HBS, we need to teach Webpack how to handle this type of file.
We are going to use a new loader here which is called handlebars loader.
And since we are using a new loader we need to install it.
We also need to install handlebars package itself.
Let's run the build process and see what happens.
It seems everything works fine.
Let's go check the dist folder.
We still have index.html inside the dist folder. Let's look inside. This time Webpack used our own
template for generating this file.
Let's have a look at it in the browser.
It seems everything  still works.
Congratulations!
In this video we learned how to tell Webpack to use our own template while generating html.