In this section we are going to learn about what pack loaders at this point you would ask what loaders
are web bag was designed to help you bundle all your dependencies into one single file.
What kind of dependencies are we talking about.
Usually dependencies are other javascript modules that your main JavaScript file requires in order to
do its job.
But we can do more than that is left back.
You can import SS files right into your javascript code you can import SAS less handle bars example
and so much more.
There are a lot of things you can import using web pack and the pickle orders are javascript libraries
that help you import all that stuff.
In the next videos we are going to talk about various loaders that you most probably will use in your
projects.