So we need to tell Webpack in which location our image is located.
We can see that it is inside the dist folder. This file is actually our image.
It has some strange name because it is an MD5 hash, but it is still our image.
We need to add 1 more property to the output configuration option.
This property is named publicPath.
And we need to specify dist here, because our image is inside the dist folder.
Don't forget the ending slash.
Now let's run Webpack in the terminal and see if anything changes in the browser.
Our build is done.
So I'm going to my browser and I will refresh my page. And voila!
Now we can see that our image is on the page.
And if you look into the developer tools you'll see that our image src begins with "dist/"
and then the MD5 hash.
So basically publicPath tells Webpack where all the generated files are located. Let's assume that
we deployed this website to the Internet and we have registered a domain
"http://the-most-awesome-website.com/".
So in order to correctly show images on this domain we would need to change the publicPath
"http://the-most-awesome-website.com/"
Let's play with it a bit.
So here inside the dist I will put "http://the-most-awesome-website.com/"
Because when I Webpack creates the path to the file it will just concatenate
these two strings. So it will be the domain name and then slash and then file name.
So now let's go to the terminal and run our build again.
Our build is done and we can go to the browser again, and refresh the page, and you cannot see the image
here because I changed the public path. But here inside the developer tools you can see that src starts
with "http://the-most-awesome-website.com/" and then the filename.
In this video we have successfully imported an image into the javascript file and became familiar with Webpack loaders.