One of the coolest features of Webpack is the ability to import CSS into javascript files.
In this video we are going to learn how to do this.
Well, frankly speaking, we can import lots of different stuff into our javascript and we have already
seen how to import images.
But why is it so cool to import CSS? With modern component-based frameworks like React or latest versions
of Angular,
it has become a best practice to separate your web application into many isolated components.
Each component has its own behavior described by javascript, and its own styles described by css.
It is much better when component styles and behavior are in the same place.
Then it is much easier to fix bugs, add new features, and to reuse such components.
Let's refactor hello-world.js file and make it a component.
It will be a button, and when user clicks on it, it will write "Hello world" to browser console.
We need to create a directory called components and inside it make another directory
called hello-world-button.
Lets move our hello-world.js file into this directory and rename it to
hello-world-button.js
Then we will refactor helloWorld function into the
HelloWorldButton class.
This class will render a button, and when somebody clicks on this button, it will print "Hello World"
into the browser.
We will create a render function which will be responsible for rendering a button and appending it to
the body DOM element. So I will remove this, and instead create a render function.
It will have caption "Hello world". Now we will append this button to the body DOM element.
Now we need to export our new component instead of
helloWorld function.
Let's go to index.js and import our new shiny component there.
It is now inside the components directory...
and inside  hello-world-button directory...
So now we need to instantiate our component and call the render function.
Let's remove addImage function for now.
Now let's run Webpack in the terminal and check what we have in the browser.
I will refresh my page, and now we don't have an image there anymore, but we have a button "Hello world".
But this button doesn't do anything yet.
If I click on it, nothing happens.
Let's go to our editor and add some functionality to it.
I will add onclick property to our button. When somebody clicks on it, it will add "p" DOM element to the
"body" DOM element with a text "Hello World".
Now it's time to create some styles. I will add classes to the button and p DOM elements.
Let's create
a new css file and put it together with our JavaScript file.
We'll also put some styles inside.
It will be like simple styles for our button specifying font size, padding, colors. And it'll be also some
simple styles for
hello-world-text.
Now we need to import CSS inside our component.
This way
people usually organize their code in modern frontend frameworks like React or latest versions
of Angular.
Inside directory named after our component, in our case hello world button, we have JavaScript file with behavior, and CSS file
with some styles
As we can guess Webpack doesn't know yet how to import CSS.
So let's teach Webpack how to do it.
We need to go to webpack.config.js and add a new rule there.
It will affect all CSS files.
Now I will specify not only one but two loaders.
And as you can see, we can not only use different loaders with Webpack, but we can also combine multiple loaders
inside one rule.
These rule tells Webpack that every time it sees a css  file, it needs to use css-loader and style-loader
in order to import it.
css-loader will read our CSS from file and style-loader will create style tags inside our HTML page
and put CSS into it. In order for this to work,
we have to install css-loader and style-loader.
So let's go to the terminal and I will install css-loader and style-loader.
I have already run this command so I have this loaders installed, but you guys need to run this.
So let's run Webpack now and check what happens in the browser.
Everything ok...
I will go to the browser and refresh my page.
And I click on the button, I see the text.
So as you can see our button became larger and greener than it was.
And when I click on it, greet text appears. It seems we have a lot of green here.
Let's go to the developer tools and check our head tag.
We have a head tag here,
and we have a style tag here, and inside the style tag we have our CSS.
So it seems everything works.
Congratulations! In this video we have successfully imported CSS into our javascript and learned how to combine multiple
loaders inside a single rule!