In the previous video we have learned how to import CSS files inside our JavaScript.
By the way we can also write our styles using SASS or LESS as well as other CSS preprocessors.
I will show you how to import sass here, but you can easily use anything you want in your application.
Let's go to our editor again and change our css into sass.
First I would change file extension into scss and then I would use some variables for font size and
color.
We will play a bit and change text color to red. Don't forget to change the import statement on the
javascript side.
Now we need to create a rule for sass files. I copy this rule for css and slightly modify it.
we need to add sass loader to the end of the chain.
Pay attention to the order in which loaders appear in the array.
Webpack processes loaders from right to left.
So first Webpack will invoke sass loader which will convert our sass to css. And it will invoke
css-loader which will take that converted css and convert it to the javascript representation.
And only then Webpack will invoke style-loader which will create style tags inside our HTML page and
put the assets into it.
Since we are using a new loader we have to install it
So you guys need to run this command.
I have already run this command before and I have sass loader installed, and this command takes some time.
Now let's run Webpack again and go to browser and check if everything still works.
I will refresh my page and make several clicks and we have red text there.
So yes it works!
Congratulations!
In this video we have successfully learned how to import scss into our Javascript.