In this video we're going to learn how to import other JavaScript files inside our JavaScript file.
What?? - you would say. I already know how to import JavaScript files!
You don't need any additional loader for that!
And you
are right.
We actually already did that.
We imported hello-world-button.js inside index.js and everything worked out of the box. So why do we need
additional loader?
Javascript language is based on EcmaScript specification and this specification is evolving all the time.
Every time new version
EcmaScript specification comes out, browsers go ahead and implement all new features.
But it takes time to implement features in all browsers, and we want to use new features right away.
We don't want to wait for several years until all browsers will support those features.
So what do we do in this situation?
Luckily, there is a transpiler out there which can help us to use all the new features
right away. It translates the modern JavaScript into old JavaScript, which is supported by all browsers and NodeJS.
This transcriber is called Babel, and we will learn how to use it
in this video. Let's go to the HelloWorldButton component. We have a lot of hard coded things here.
Let's take a css class of our button as an example and put it into a separate property.
It will not make our code super clean, but it is good enough for this example.
We'll take this class and create a class property here called buttonCssClass.
And here we will use our property, like that. So this is what is called class property and it isn't supported
by most browsers and NodeJS at the moment of creating this video.
Most browsers only allow methods inside javascript classes, but not properties like our
buttonCssClass.
If we run Webpack now, it will throw an error.
Let's check it.
Yeah.
There is an error here, and this error also says "You may need an appropriate loader to handle this file
type".
And actually Webpack is right.
Even though class properties are not part of official EcmaScript specification, at least at the time
this video is being created, but we can still use them with Webpack.
We just need to use a special loader for that, which is called babel-loader.
Let's create a new rule for JavaScript files. We will go to webpack.config.js and add a new rule here.
This rule will be applicable to all JavaScript files except those files which are located in node_modules
folder.
We will tell Webpack to use babel-loader for these files.
We need to specify a couple of options for babel-loader.
As you'll see in the moment we can specify additional options for any loader.
Of course this loader should support these options.
First option is called presets.
We need a special babel preset which is called "env". Env preset will help us to compile EcmaScript 6 and
above code down to EcmaScript 5. Env preset includes all the features from the latest EcmaScript specification.
As I already said earlier,
Class properties are not part of the official EcmaScript specification.
So we need a special babel plugin to support this feature.
This babel plugin is called "transform-class-properties".
If you want to use another modern javascript feature which is not supported by most browsers yet, you
should find a babel plugin for that
and dd it to the list of plugins here. We can use as many babel plugins as we want.
No we need to install babel-core, babel-loader, babel-preset and transform-class-properties
babel plugin.
So I'm going to my terminal and I will install all this stuff.
If we run Webpack now, it will use babel-loader for our JavaScript files, and if it happens that our
javascript uses newest features that are not in official specification yet, Webpack we'll convert that
code to older javascript which is understood by all browsers and NodeJS.
This time our build works fine.
Let's go to the browser now and check if everything is still OK there.
I will refresh my page...
As you can see everything is working. In this video
we have learned how to use modern javascript features in our project even though this features are so
new that they haven't been included in the official script specification yet!