Quite often we need to create Web applications completely from scratch and we have to create all of
the components by ourselves.
But it is not always the case.
Sometimes we can use already existing libraries.
This video is about one of the most popular front end component libraries in the world.
Bootstrap. To be more precise,
this video is about how to use bootstrap together with webpack.
For those of you who never used bootstrap it is an open source toolkit for developing with
HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
It allows you to build responsive mobile first projects or quickly create prototypes for your ideas.
It includes responsive grid system, extensive prebuild components and powerful plugins built on jQuery.
You can learn more about bootstrap
on its official website getbootstrap dot com.
First let's have a look at our current project.
We have a single page application with a heading and a button "hello world". When we click on the button,
it shows the text "Hello world" below.
We'd like to include some bootstrap components on this page.
First we need to install bootstrap.
There is a possibility to install bootstrap as an NPM package and include it inside our package.json.
So I am going into my terminal and typing npm install bootstrap --save. We are using
--save option here because we need bootstrap to be included in the resulting bundle.
If we used --save-dev option, then bootstrap would be also installed inside node modules
as a project dependency, but it would not be included in the resulting bundle. Bootstrap depends on
jQuery and proper dot js.
So we need to install these libraries as well.
Now when we have bootstrap installed, let's include it inside our index.js file.
I am going to my editor. index.js, and what we need to do here is import bootstrap.
This way
we include javascript from bootstrap.
We also need to include css. There are actually two ways to include css from bootstrap into our
project.
First option is to import precompiled sass.
This option allows you to customize bootstrap to your needs and use the source files as part of your
project's bundling process.
This option requires a bit of additional work in order to set up. Second option is to import already
compiled ready to use css.
It is the easy option and we will use it in this video.
So let's import our ready to use css from bootstrap.
Now
Let's go to our page template and add a couple of bootstrap components on our page.
I will add an alert and a dropdown.
First let's add an alert.
I will add it inside the body tag. And now let's add a dropdown as well.
I would like to add some simple styling to our dropdown.
Therefore I will put a custom class on it.
Now let's add some styles for our dropdown.
We'll create an SCSS file for our index page and call it index dot SCSS.
It will contain some simple positioning  styles.
So here I am specifying my dropdown class and these are simple styles. Let's import our styles inside
the index dot J S file.
Now it seems everything is ready. Lets run npm run build in the terminal and check what we
have in the browser.
I am going to the terminal.
Here we can run npm run build.
Let's wait a couple of seconds.
It seems our build is ready.
Now let's start our application.
It says application is running in port 3000. Now let's go to our browser and check it. I will refresh
my page.
And here we see our page with the alert from bootstrap here and with a dropdown component from bootstrap.
And if we click on our dropdown component, we can see some dropdown items inside. So in this video we
have learned how to use bootstrap together with webpack.