In the previous video we have learned how to use bootstrap together with webpack.
We learned that there are two ways to include css from bootstrap into our project. We can either import pre-compiled sass
or import compiled and ready-to-use css. In the previous video we imported ready-to-use css.
So in this video I will show you how to import precompiled sass.
This method allows you to customize bootstrap to your needs and use the bootstrap source files as part
of the bundling process.
However, for this option to work, we need to modify our rule for scss files and install
a couple of conditional loaders.
So let's go to webpack.production.config.js
and do it.
So now we are inside webpack configuration. And we need to modify this rule which relates to SCSS files.
I will align a little bit this loaders.
And now we need to add an additional order to our rule. This loader is called postcss loader
and we will put it between css loader and sass loader.
Here is
how it looks like.
CSS loader lets you convert modern CSS into something that most browsers can understand.
We can provide various plugins to postcss loader. Autoprefixer is a postcss plugin that allows
to parse CSS and add vendor prefixes to CSS rules.
Precss is a postcss plugin  that lets you use latest CSS features like color functions,
logical and custom properties, media query ranges, and image sets right now. So now we need to install
postcss loader together
with autoprefixer and precss. I'm going to my terminal.
And now I need to install these things.
Now we need to include sass files from Bootstrap inside our indexed.scss file.
And going to my editor to the index.scss file.
And here right at the beginning of the file I will include the bootstrap files.
Yeah
After this is done we can go to that index.js
And right here
we don't need this line anymore, so we can simply remove it. We used this line when we imported
ready-to-use css in the previous video.
We still need these lines though, because they... the first line imports javascript from Bootstrap,
and this line imports our index.scss  file. Let's go to the terminal and run
our build.
Our build is done and let's start the application.
Application is running.
So now we can go to our browser and check what we have there.
I will refresh my page.
And now we can see that we still have a bootstrap alert
at the top of the page and a dropdown component at the top right corner.
Everything still works even after we changed the way how we include bootstrap css into a project.
So in this video we have learned the second way of importing bootstrap css using webpack.